Marek Ventur Senior Software Developer

marekventur.com | mail@marekventur.de | github.com/marekventur

Currently working for AWS's machine learning org, having moved there from Amazon Retail. First-day employee at gaming-startup Gamevy and data engineer at the music website Last.fm. Worked at IBM while doing my Bachelor.

I have worked on petabyte-scale databases all the way to one-off game prototypes. I have experience in leading teams and projects and my passion is for maths and algorithms, with a focus on research.

Helped design and build digital conference badges for the hacker camp Electromagnetic Field.

Backend Frontend Data Languages

Java, Kotlin, Python JS, WebGL, HTML, CSS SQL, Hadoop, PyTorch English, German, (Spanish)

## **Selected projects**

Frame classification: Research into categorizing Java methods by using unsupervised learning.

Anomaly Detection: Prototyping, designing and launching CodeGuru Profiler's Anomaly Detection feature.

Launching an AWS service Amazon CodeGuru Profiler. Leading UI and UX work

Petabyte-scale database: Worked on low latency data store that acted as an entry point to Amazon's product pipeline, using

one of the largest DynamoDB tables worldwide

Realtime Scrobbles: Second-level-resolution of Last.fm's listening data, streamed via websockets

## **Employment history**

### AWS, Machine Learning (May 2019 - Present), London

Software Development Engineer

Developed and launched Amazon CodeGuru Profiler

- Launched new AWS service
- Leading **UX/UI** for the AWS console component and the profiler visualizations.
- Prototyped, developed, designed and launched anomaly detection feature

## Amazon (Oct 2017 - May 2019), London

Software Development Engineer

Working on services that enable Amazon's massive product catalog

- High-level design and implementation to enable removal of legacy services.
- Day-to-day running of service, including tier-1 on-call shifts
- Performance optimisation

# Gamevy (Aug 2013 - Sep 2017), London

Senior Developer/Project Manager

As the first-day engineer at startup Gamevy I've worked on game design, frontend, backend and operations, as well as acting as project manager. Frequent contributer to PIXI.js.

- **Developing game concepts** for the majority of Gamevy's games to date.
- Project management for various games
- $\bullet$   $\mbox{\sc Probabilistic modelling}$  to verify mathematical correctness

### Last.fm (Oct 2011 - Aug 2013), London

Web and Data Developer

Initially front-end developer, later move to data team.

- Data developer (Hadoop, Hive, SQL)
- Designed and implemented main parts of realtime charts

### **Education**

### Baden-Wuerttemberg Cooperative State University Mannheim (Oct 2008 - Nov 2011)

Corporate Student Program, IBM, Germany BSc Science, Business IT